♪ In the face of turmoil ♪
♪ 혼란에 직면하여 ♪
♪ Its roots hold firmly ♪
♪뿌리가 굳건히 자리잡고 있습니다 ♪
♪ To this piece of land ♪
♪ 이 땅으로 ♪
♪ Searching for the waves ♪
♪파도를 찾아서 ♪
♪ My leaves flutter ♪
♪ 나뭇잎이 펄럭인다 ♪
♪ The horizon ♪
♪ 지평선 ♪
♪ Dealing from afar ♪
♪멀리서 상대하기 ♪
♪ At the end of the world ♪
♪ 세상의 끝에서 ♪
♪ It's eternity ♪
♪영원하다 ♪
♪ When we meet and then part ♪
♪만나고 헤어질 때 ♪
♪ When we depend on each other and then move away ♪
♪서로 의지 하다가 멀어질 때 ♪
♪ I never forgot it ♪
♪나는 그것을 결코 잊지 않았다 ♪
♪ By cutting the shine of swords ♪
♪검의 광택을 잘라내서 ♪
♪ Through the dappled sky ♪
♪얼룩진 하늘을 통해 ♪
♪ Dreams that fall ♪
♪떨어지는 꿈♪
♪ Shatter in the wind ♪
♪ 바람에 부서지네 ♪
♪ As the wind cuts through the waves ♪
♪바람이 파도를 가르듯이 ♪
♪ Watch thousands of candles cross ♪
♪ 수천 개의 촛불이 교차하는 모습을 보세요 ♪
♪ The vast land and the boundless sea ♪
♪ 광활한 대지와 끝없는 바다 ♪
♪ Armor and red robes flying high ♪
♪ 높이 날아오르는 갑옷과 붉은 로브 ♪
♪ Against bitterness, intense emotions and joyful adventures ♪
♪ 씁쓸함, 강렬한 감정, 그리고 즐거운 모험에 맞서 ♪
♪ I just wish you were by my side ♪
♪당신이 내 곁에 있었으면 좋겠어요 ♪
♪ Make the most of what life has to offer ♪
♪ 인생이 제공하는 것을 최대한 활용하세요 ♪
♪ Like tall trees with interconnected roots, I will accompany you to the ends ♪
♪ 뿌리가 얽힌 큰 나무처럼 나는 끝까지 당신과 동행하겠습니다 ♪
♪ Watching the fireflies land on our shoulders ♪
♪ 반딧불이가 어깨 위에 내려앉는 모습을 지켜보세요 ♪
♪ Don't regret it, there are no doubts in this world ♪
♪ 후회하지 마세요. 이 세상에 의심은 없습니다 ♪
= Wonders of love =
= 사랑의 경이로움 =
= Episode 7 =
= 7화 =
- Lieutenant. - What is the situation?
- 중위. - 상황은 어떻습니까?
The Bingzhou garrison is about to collapse.
Bingzhou 수비대 가 곧 무너질 것입니다.
Some soldiers left the city and escaped to Jianzhou.
일부 군인은 도시를 떠나 Jianzhou로 탈출했습니다.
The rest have mostly given up.
나머지는 대부분 포기했습니다.
Now we count the prisoners, food supplies, stamps, letters
이제 우리는 죄수, 식량, 우표, 편지를 계산합니다.
and many other urgent things.
그 밖에도 많은 긴급한 일들.
Did you touch Han Li?
한리 만졌어?
When Han Li saw the situation,
상황을 본 한리는
He escaped with the help of his personal guards.
그는 개인 경비원의 도움으로 탈출했습니다 .
But I have sent our men to look for him.
그러나 나는 그를 찾으라고 우리 부하들을 보냈습니다 .
The city gate is closed.
성문은 닫혀 있습니다.
I'm sure he's still in Bingzhou.
나는 그가 아직 Bingzhou에 있다고 확신합니다.
Listen.
듣다.
We have to capture Han Li before the Zhenxi Army.
진시군보다 먼저 한리를 붙잡아야 합니다 .
See that.
저거 봐.
(Which)
(어느)
Guards!
근위 연대!
Mr. Lv.
Mr. Lv.
Mr. Lv fainted suddenly.
Lv 씨는 갑자기 기절했습니다.
Alú escapes!
알루가 탈출해요!
Señor Shiqi.
시치 선생님.
This time I have brought many men.
이번에는 남자들을 많이 데리고 왔습니다.
Where is Han Li?
한리는 어디에 있나요?
Have you caught it?
잡았나요?
I made a deal with the Cui family.
나는 Cui 가족과 거래를 했습니다.
Whoever catches Han Li first will take over Bingzhou.
한리(Han Li)를 먼저 잡는 사람이 빙 저우(Bingzhou)를 차지하게 됩니다.
Han Li fled as soon as the battle began.
한리는 전투가 시작되자마자 도망쳤다.
But Bao chases after him.
하지만 바오는 그를 쫓는다.
Let's go capture that cunning man.
그 교활한 남자를 잡으러 가자.
Chen Xing.
첸 싱.
Lieutenant, Han Li is not in the car.
한리 중위는 차에 없습니다.
In fact it is clever.
사실 그것은 영리하다.
Qiucui, don't worry.
Qiucui, 걱정하지 마세요.
Our servants
우리의 종들
They are on guard below.
그들은 아래를 지키고 있습니다.
Nobody can enter.
누구도 들어갈 수 없습니다.
Lady, they say
아가씨, 사람들이 말하길
that the army will break into the city and sack it
군대가 그 도시에 침입하여 약탈할 것이라고
and do all kinds of evil.
온갖 악을 행합니다.
Will our servants be able to stop them?
우리 하인들이 그들을 막을 수 있을까요?
If they can stop them,
그들을 막을 수 있다면,
We will be safe and healthy.
우리는 안전하고 건강할 것입니다.
If they don't stop them,
만약 그들이 그들을 막지 못한다면,
What's the point of being afraid right now?
지금 두려워하는 게 무슨 소용이 있나요 ?
This is the Third Lady's fault.
이것은 세 번째 부인의 잘못입니다.
If he does not curse you with the Master,
만일 그가 주인과 함께 너를 저주하지 아니하면
You wouldn't have to volunteer to come.
자원해서 오실 필요는 없습니다.
to Bingzhou for ancestor worship.
조상 숭배를 위해 Bingzhou에 .
If it weren't for the Third Lady,
세 번째 부인이 아니었다면,
we wouldn't be here in Bingzhou
우리는 여기 Bingzhou에 없을 것입니다
(Prime Minister Gu's daughter,) and we wouldn't be in danger now.
(구총리의 딸,) 그리고 우리는 이제 위험에 처하지 않을 것입니다.
(Gu Wan'niang) Qiucui, that's not true.
(Gu Wan'niang) Qiucui, 그건 사실이 아닙니다.
The third sister is right.
셋째 언니 말이 맞아요.
My father has six daughters.
아버지에게는 여섯 명의 딸이 있습니다.
I'm the only one who isn't smart
똑똑하지 않은 사람은 나뿐이야
and has no rescue qualities.
구조 특성이 없습니다.
If I don't work harder,
내가 더 열심히 일하지 않으면,
I will be even more useless.
나는 더욱 쓸모없게 될 것이다.
Third Lady was simply spouting nonsense.
세 번째 부인은 그저 말도 안되는 소리를 내뱉고 있었습니다.
Don't take it personally.
개인적으로 받아들이지 마십시오.
Great Governor Sun wanted to appoint my father as prime minister.
손태사는 나의 아버지를 총리로 임명하고 싶어했습니다.
My father refused.
아버지는 거절하셨습니다.
Then, he was sent to jail.
그 후 그는 감옥에 보내졌습니다.
All royal families in the capital city
수도의 모든 왕족
He admired him for his incorruptible integrity.
그는 그의 부패하지 않는 성실성을 존경했습니다.
Now that he's finally free,
이제 그는 마침내 자유로워졌으니,
You cannot leave the capital city.
수도를 떠날 수는 없습니다.
I am lucky to be able
나는 운이 좋게도 그럴 수 있다
travel to Bingzhou to pay tribute
빙저우에 가서 조공을 바치다
to our ancestors in his name.
그의 이름으로 우리 조상들에게.
If you are always like this,
늘 이렇다면
When can you live with your head held high?
언제 머리를 높이 들고 살 수 있습니까 ?
Even those servants in the residence
그 집 하인들도
They dare to treat you rudely now.
그들은 지금 감히 당신을 무례하게 대합니다.
Don't worry, Master.
걱정하지 마세요, 선생님.
Persecutors have been fooled with that car.
박해자들은 그 차에 속았습니다 .
Is there somewhere to hide here?
여기에 숨을 곳이 있나요?
If you can seize someone's private residence
타인의 개인 주택을 압류할 수 있는 경우
in broad daylight,
대낮에,
Why don't you look to hide?
숨어서 보지 그래 ?
Mr. Han has always been a hero.
한씨는 언제나 영웅이었습니다.
Miss.
놓치다.
But now, you are hiding in a lady's room.
그런데 지금 당신은 여자화장실에 숨어있습니다.
Gives you no shame?
부끄러움도 안 주나요?
Mr. Han.
그 씨.
Don't you think you've fallen too low
당신이 너무 낮아졌다고 생각하지 않나요?
If you have to keep a weak lady kidnapped?
약한 여자를 납치해야 한다면?
You can't hit me.
당신은 나를 때릴 수 없습니다.
Since you are young master Cui study partner,
당신은 젊은 스승 Cui 학습 파트너이기 때문에,
Now that Bingzhou has fallen,
이제 Bingzhou가 무너졌으니,
the Zhenxi Army has more power.
Zhenxi 군대는 더 많은 힘을 가지고 있습니다.
Since you don't value Young Master Cui,
당신은 최영대사를 소중히 여기지 않으니까 ,
Maybe you should join the Zhenxi Army instead.
어쩌면 대신 Zhenxi 군대에 합류해야 할 수도 있습니다 .
You are already
당신은 이미
in such a difficult situation.
그런 어려운 상황에서.
And yet, you're worried about my future.
그런데도 당신은 내 미래를 걱정하고 있어요.
I will never regret
나는 결코 후회하지 않을 것이다
know you.
너를 안다.
And thanks
그리고 감사합니다
for putting me in your good graces.
당신의 좋은 은총에 저를 넣어 주셔서.
What's the point of putting you in my good graces?
당신을 나의 좋은 은총에 두는 게 무슨 소용이 있나요 ?
Will you let me go?
날 놓아줄래?
You have misunderstood me, Lord Han.
한경님, 제 말을 오해하셨습니다.
I can not thank you enough.
나는 충분히 감사할 수 없습니다.
Why would it bring you harm?
왜 그것이 당신에게 해를 끼칠까요?
Everyone in town says
동네 사람들이 다 그러는데
that you are good at business.
당신이 사업을 잘한다는 것.
And that you are a rich man.
그리고 당신은 부자입니다.
Now that I have been abandoned by the Cui family,
이제 나는 추이 가문에게 버림받았고 ,
I don't have anything.
나는 아무것도 가지고 있지 않습니다.
Please be understanding
이해해주세요
and give me a hand.
그리고 나에게 도움을 주세요.
Take them.
가져가세요.
These pieces of jewelry are very valuable.
이 보석들은 매우 귀중합니다.
take them
가져가라
and join the Zhenxi Army.
Zhenxi 군대에 합류하세요.
Miss!
놓치다!
Do not stay!
유지하지 않습니다!
Miss.
놓치다.
If she comes here, I will kill her.
그녀가 여기 오면 나는 그녀를 죽일 것이다.
Miss!
놓치다!
Miss.
놓치다.
Miss, please forgive me.
아가씨, 용서해주세요.
Thanks for saving my life.
내 생명을 구해주셔서 감사합니다.
Do not move!
이동하지 않습니다!
Lieutenant, should we fight them for him?
중위님, 그를 위해 그들과 싸워야 할까요?
I recognize defeat.
나는 패배를 인정한다.
I'm not anyone who can't admit defeat.
나는 패배를 인정하지 못하는 사람이 아니다 .
Are you okay, miss?
괜찮아요 아가씨?
Miss.
놓치다.
Hurry up.
서둘러요.
Come here.
이리 오세요.
Señor Shiqi.
시치 선생님.
Finally, we managed to capture this cunning man.
마침내 우리는 이 교활한 남자를 붙잡았습니다.
It's too late for the Cui Army.
Cui 군대에게는 너무 늦었습니다.
Now Han Li belongs to us.
이제 한리는 우리의 것입니다.
Congratulations, Li Ni.
축하해요, 리니님.
Since you have managed to capture Han Li,
한리를 잡는 데 성공했으니,
I will honor our deal.
나는 우리의 거래를 존중할 것입니다.
Bingzhou belongs to the Zhenxi Army now.
Bingzhou는 현재 Zhenxi 군대에 속해 있습니다.
Gracias.
그라시아스.
Han Li has been captured by the Zhenxi Army.
Han Li는 Zhenxi 군대에 의해 체포되었습니다 .
According to our deal, bingzhou belongs to them now.
우리의 거래에 따르면 Bingzhou는 이제 그들의 소유입니다.
That?
저것?
When did they make that deal?
언제 그 거래를 했나요?
with the Zhenxi army?
Zhenxi 군대와 함께?
How will you be able to do it?
어떻게 할 수 있나요?
Lieutenant, why didn't you tell me?
중위님, 왜 나한테 말하지 않았나요?
She already informed me about it beforehand.
그녀는 이미 나에게 그 사실을 미리 알려주었다.
She barely followed my order.
그녀는 내 명령을 거의 따르지 않았습니다.
The Zhenxi Army is short on food.
Zhenxi 군대는 식량이 부족합니다.
Of
의
informed Young Master about it.
이에 대해 Young Master에게 알렸습니다.
As soon as we entered the city,
우리는 시내에 들어오자마자
We sent our men to clean up the food supplies.
우리는 식량을 청소하기 위해 부하들을 보냈습니다 .
Now, although the Zhenxi army has taken over Bingzhou,
이제 진희군이 빙저우를 점령했지만,
They still don't have food.
아직 음식이 없어요.
I see.
알겠어요.
I would like to ask you please, Li.
부탁드리고 싶습니다 , 리씨.
Are you finally going to let yourself help?
드디어 스스로 도와주실 건가요 ?
We are Family.
우리는 가족.
There is no need to be polite.
예의를 갖추실 필요는 없습니다.
You are the commander of our army.
당신은 우리 군대의 사령관입니다.
Just give me your order.
주문만 해주세요.
Now that our army is in the city,
이제 우리 군대가 도시에 있으므로
We have to remain alert in case the Zhenxi Army
진시군이 공격할 경우를 대비해 경계해야 합니다.
He has an ulterior motive.
그에게는 숨은 동기가 있습니다.
I hope you can
나는 당신이 할 수 있기를 바랍니다
stationing a troop outside the city.
도시 외곽에 군대를 주둔시키다 .
If something happens in the city,
도시에 무슨 일이 생기면
You can support us from outside.
외부에서 우리를 지원할 수 있습니다.
Just in case.
혹시라도.
Season...
계절...
Contribute a troop outside?
외부에 병력을 파견하시겠습니까?
I'm sure you have a reason for this decision.
나는 당신이 이런 결정을 내린 데에는 이유가 있다고 확신합니다 .
I will lead one troop and one station out of the city at a time.
나는 한 번에 한 부대와 한 기지를 도시 밖으로 이끌겠습니다 .
Gracias.
그라시아스.
We are Family.
우리는 가족.
There is no need to be polite.
예의를 갖추실 필요는 없습니다.
I know you don't like it.
나는 당신이 그것을 좋아하지 않는다는 것을 알고 있습니다.
That's why
그렇기 때문에
I sent him away from the city.
나는 그를 도시에서 멀리 보냈습니다.
Thank you, Young Master.
고마워요, 영 마스터님.
No wonder Shu is nowhere to be found.
슈가 어디에도 없는 것도 당연합니다.
You sent him outside the city early in the morning
이른 아침에 그를 성 밖으로 보내셨느니라
to keep an eye on Cui Li.
Cui Li를 감시하기 위해.
You know me well, Ying.
당신은 나를 잘 알고 있어요, 잉.
Have some tea.
차 좀 드세요.
Let me pour it out for you.
내가 당신을 위해 부어 드리겠습니다.
Say it again if you dare.
용기가 있다면 다시 말해보세요.
GOOD.
좋은.
Since you are slightly deaf, I will say it again.
귀가 조금 들리므로 다시 한 번 말씀드리겠습니다.
The Cui Army
추이군
must deliver
배달해야 함
the foods you have eaten
당신이 먹은 음식들
and leave the city.
그리고 도시를 떠나세요.
The Zhenxi Army
진시군
He is magnanimous and kind.
그는 관대하고 친절합니다.
Since we are both
우리 둘 다니까
They are fighting for the same throne,
같은 왕좌를 두고 싸우고 있는
we will let you rest in Bingzhou
우리는 당신을 Bingzhou에서 쉬게 할 것입니다
for one night before your departure.
출발 전 하룻밤.
What do you think?
어떻게 생각하나요?
The Zhenxi army is generous enough, right?
Zhenxi 군대는 충분히 관대합니다. 그렇죠?
We are the ones who took down Bingzhou.
Bingzhou를 무너뜨린 것은 바로 우리입니다.
The food supplies belong to the party that entered the city first.
식량 공급은 도시에 먼저 들어간 파티의 것입니다.
Even though we made a deal with you,
우리가 당신과 거래를 했어도,
now you have taken over Bingzhou.
이제 당신은 Bingzhou를 점령했습니다.
Why do we have to give you food supplies?
왜 우리가 당신에게 식량을 주어야 합니까 ?
Do you think I'll be afraid of you
내가 당신을 두려워할 것 같나요?
just because you slapped the table?
단지 네가 테이블을 쳤기 때문에?
We went down Bingzhou together.
우리는 함께 Bingzhou로 내려갔습니다.
Without the Zhenxi Army,
진시군이 없다면,
Han Li would have escaped to Jianzhou
Han Li는 Jianzhou로 탈출했을 것입니다
and tried to reclaim Bingzhou.
Bingzhou를 되찾으려고 노력했습니다.
How dare you say that.
감히 그런 말을 합니까?
I said!
나는 말했다!
Give back our food supplies!
우리 식량을 돌려주세요!
Say it again!
다시 말해보세요!
Are you really deaf?
당신은 정말 귀머거리인가요?
If we don't attack the city,
도시를 공격하지 않으면
you wouldn't have time to catch Han Li.
Han Li를 잡을 시간이 없을 것입니다 .
Return our food supplies
우리의 식량을 돌려주세요
and get out of Bingzhou!
Bingzhou에서 나가세요!
Divina.
디비나.
Bro.
형.
I'll kill you.
나는 당신을 죽일 것이다.
Han Li does not have the tiger bead.
한리는 호랑이구슬을 갖고 있지 않다.
Keep searching.
계속 검색하세요.
Roger that.
알 겠어.
- That's complete nonsense. - Bright.
- 완전 말도 안되는 소리네요. - 밝은.
I'll kill you.
나는 당신을 죽일 것이다.
They are looking for
그들은 찾고 있습니다
Han Li's residence completely.
한리의 거주지는 완전히.
It seems that
것 같다
the tiger account is not with Han Li.
호랑이 계정은 한리님의 계정이 아닙니다.
Young Master Cui there
거기에 젊은 스승님 추이
has a fierce reputation on the battlefield.
전장에서 엄청난 명성을 얻었습니다 .
But now that I've seen it in person,
그런데 이제 직접 보니,
He is just a weak and weak man.
그는 단지 약하고 약한 사람일 뿐입니다.
Never judge a book by its cover.
겉만보고 남을 판단하지 마라.
He's just a cute boy.
그는 단지 귀여운 소년입니다.
How dare you say I didn't join the fight.
내가 싸움에 참여하지 않았다고 감히 말합니까 ?
You were just a baby
넌 그냥 아기였어
when I was fighting in battle!
내가 전투에서 싸울 때!
We will fight if they dare!
그들이 감히 싸우면 우리는 싸울 것입니다!
- Let's go then! - Come on!
- 그럼 가자! - 어서 해봐요!
I'm not a coward who's afraid of you.
나는 당신을 두려워하는 겁쟁이가 아닙니다.
Ven.
Ven.
I'm going to teach you a lesson,
제가 한 수 가르쳐 드리겠습니다.
brother
형제
(Tang problem)
(탱 문제)
Are you hungry?
너 배고프 니?
I asked someone early in the morning.
아침 일찍 누군가에게 물었습니다 .
They are your favorites.
그들은 당신이 가장 좋아하는 것입니다.
Thank you, Young Master.
고마워요, 영 마스터님.
You are quite strong.
당신은 꽤 강해요.
It's delicious.
이 맛있어요.
Where are you hitting?
어디를 치고 있습니까?
Yo...
에야디야...
Let me help you clean.
청소를 도와드리겠습니다.
¡Detente!
긴장 완화!
I'm hungry.
배고파요.
Let's eat first.
먼저 먹자.
¿Comer?
올 사람?
I'm not hungry.
난 배고프지 않아.
I say I'm hungry.
나는 배가 고프다고 말한다.
Lieutenant.
대장 보좌.
It seems that Li Ni found
리니가 찾은 것 같아요
the pivot you have lost.
당신이 잃어버린 피벗.
I never thought
나는 결코 생각하지 못했다
that Imperial grandfather,
그 황실 할아버지,
the marshal of the Zhenxi Army,
진시군 사령관,
I would be so greedy.
나는 너무 욕심이 많을 것입니다.
He found your nail but refused to come back.
그는 당신의 손톱을 찾았 지만 돌아오지 않았습니다.
And he even wears it openly in his head.
그리고 그는 심지어 그것을 머리 속에 공개적으로 착용합니다.
How shameless of him.
그 사람은 얼마나 뻔뻔한가.
I'll go get it for you.
내가 가서 사러 갈게.
No.
아니요.
Don't make trouble.
문제를 일으키지 마십시오.
Look at the big picture.
큰 그림을 보세요.
I thought that the lieutenant
중위라고 생각했는데
lost its pivot.
중심을 잃었습니다.
Why does Li Ni have it?
왜 Li Ni가 그것을 가지고 있습니까?
Lieutenant He gave it to you.
중위님이 주셨네요.
Qixi Lantern Festival
치시 등불 축제
It has always been an important festival in Bingzhou.
Bingzhou에서는 항상 중요한 축제였습니다 .
Now, we have two large armies in Bingzhou.
이제 Bingzhou에는 두 개의 큰 군대가 있습니다 .
Who do you think
당신은 누구라고 생각합니까?
Will you accept our invitation?
우리의 초대를 수락하시겠습니까?
I hope there is no fight.
싸움이 없기를 바랍니다.
Ask that pretty face of yours
그 예쁜 얼굴을 물어봐
to go out.
외출하다.
Who is a pretty face?
얼굴이 예쁜 사람은 누구인가요?
The Zhenxi Army is the pretty face that wants a free ride.
진시군은 무임승차를 원하는 예쁜 얼굴이다.
Both armies fight a lot.
두 군대는 많이 싸운다.
A fight will eventually break out.
결국 싸움이 일어나게 됩니다.
If the city cannot be at peace,
도시가 평화롭지 못하다면,
It is we who will be affected.
영향을 받는 사람은 바로 우리입니다 .
I'm sorry for the wait.
기다리게 해서 미안해요.
No need to apologize.
사과할 필요는 없습니다.
According to our Young Master,
우리 젊은 스승님에 따르면,
Bingzhou has just begun to settle down.
Bingzhou는 이제 막 정착하기 시작했습니다 .
Everyone continues to live in fear.
모두가 계속 두려움 속에 살고 있습니다.
We need to hold a lively Lantern Festival celebration.
활기찬 등불축제를 열어야 합니다 .
Life can only go on
인생은 계속될 수 밖에 없다
when people feel safe.
사람들이 안전하다고 느낄 때.
And bring peace to the people
그리고 사람들에게 평화를 가져다주세요.
That's why we fight for the throne.
그것이 우리가 왕좌를 위해 싸우는 이유입니다.
Everyone in the Cui army,
Cui 군대의 모든 사람들,
including the Young Master, will attend the festival.
Young Master를 포함하여 축제에 참석할 예정입니다.
Please take care of us on that day
그날 우리를 잘 부탁해
Of course.
물론.
It seems that
것 같다
the Zhenxi army is not attending.
Zhenxi 군대 는 참석하지 않습니다.
No, that's not true.
아니요, 사실이 아닙니다.
Young Master Cui has said everything
Young Master Cui가 모든 것을 말했습니다.
that my general transmits.
내 장군이 전송하는 것입니다.
The Zhenxi army will attend the festival as well.
Zhenxi 군대 도 축제에 참석할 예정입니다.
Gracias.
그라시아스.
What's the point of having good hearing?
청력이 좋으면 무슨 소용이 있나요?
You speak so slowly,
말투가 너무 느리네요
Why are you here, Imperial Grandfather?
왜 여기에 계십니까, 황실 할아버지?
I need to ask the lieutenant something .
중위에게 물어볼 게 있어요.
She's just a lieutenant.
그녀는 단지 중위입니다.
If it concerns military matters,
군사 문제에 관한 것이라면,
You can only talk to me about it.
당신은 그것에 대해서만 나에게 이야기할 수 있습니다.
It's a minor matter.
사소한 문제입니다.
No need to bother you.
귀찮게 할 필요가 없습니다.
I heard that Lieutenant He
그 중위님이라고 들었어요
He was stranded in Han Li's residence a few days ago.
그는 며칠 전 한리의 집에 갇혀 있었습니다 .
And she only came out alive
그리고 그녀는 살아서 나왔지
because I was under your care.
왜냐하면 나는 당신의 보살핌을 받았기 때문입니다.
I should prepare a banquet
연회를 준비해야겠어
to thank
고마움을 전하기 위해
for your help.
너의 도움으로.
The Cui Army is the main army fighting for the throne.
최군은 왕위를 놓고 싸우는 주력군이다 .
It is my duty.
그것은 나의 의무이다.
You are too kind.
당신은 너무 친절.
I grew up
내가 자란
with Lieutenant Him since he was young.
어렸을 때부터 그 중위와 함께.
We have a special relationship.
우리는 특별한 관계를 가지고 있습니다.
So, taking care of the lieutenant,
그래서 중위를 돌보고,
you have taken care of me too.
당신도 나를 돌봐줬어요.
I knew you would come.
나는 당신이 올 것이라는 것을 알았습니다.
Why are you here, Young Master?
왜 여기 계세요, 영 마스터님?
I just want to visit you.
나는 단지 당신을 방문하고 싶습니다.
Greetings, Your Majesty.
안녕하세요, 폐하.
You may be calm
안심하셔도 됩니다
It was urgent today.
오늘은 급했습니다.
You're not hurt, are you?
당신은 다치지 않았죠?
Is a doctor needed?
의사가 필요합니까?
Right now, General Pei Yuan
지금 페이위안 장군은
He has already sent a doctor to see me.
그는 이미 나를 만나기 위해 의사를 보냈습니다 .
Fortunately, I only have some minor cuts.
다행히 약간의 상처만 남았네요.
Nothing serious.
심각한 것은 아닙니다.
I'm here to thank you.
나는 당신에게 감사하기 위해 여기에 있습니다.
If it weren't for you today,
오늘 당신이 아니었다면,
I would have died.
나는 죽었을 것이다.
There's no need.
필요하지 않습니다.
It is not a big thing.
그것은 큰 일이 아니다.
Do not address me as Your Highness.
저를 전하라고 부르지 마십시오.
Call me with my title in the army.
군대에서의 직함을 알려주세요.
Ven.
Ven.
The weather has turned cold.
날씨가 추워졌습니다.
And you're not dressed properly because of the cold.
그리고 당신은 추위 때문에 제대로 옷을 입지 않았습니다 .
No wonder you cough.
기침하는 것도 당연합니다.
If Taozi discovers this,
Taozi가 이것을 발견하면
She will teach you again.
그녀가 당신을 다시 가르쳐 줄 것입니다.
I'm fine.
잘 지내요.
Today, after keeping a close eye on Li Ni,
오늘은 리니를 유심히 관찰한 끝에
In fact, he is an outstanding commander as you said.
사실 그 분은 말씀하신 대로 뛰어난 사령관이십니다.
We should never underestimate it.
우리는 그것을 결코 과소평가해서는 안 됩니다.
Indeed, Li Ni is a wise strategist.
실제로 Li Ni는 현명한 전략가입니다.
The Zhenxi Army is a formidable force.
Zhenxi 군대는 강력한 힘입니다.
If we can fight together,
함께 싸울 수 있다면,
We can achieve victory with half the effort.
우리는 절반의 노력으로 승리할 수 있습니다 .
But if we become enemies,
하지만 우리가 적이 된다면,
to be honest,
솔직히 말하자면,
with an opponent like Li Ni,
Li Ni 같은 상대와 함께
I fear that
나는 그것이 두렵다
that we will not be able to defeat them.
우리는 그들을 이길 수 없을 것입니다.
The Zhenxi Army is tied up fighting for the throne.
Zhenxi 군대는 왕좌를 위해 싸우고 있습니다.
It does not matter that,
그것은 중요하지 않습니다.
They will not become our enemies.
그들은 우리의 적이 되지 않을 것입니다.
It's better to be safe than sorry.
후회하는 것보다 안전한 것이 낫습니다.
Do you have any family in this city?
이 도시에 가족이 있나요?
I can ask Bao to send someone to take you home.
Bao에게 당신을 집으로 데려갈 사람을 보내달라고 요청할 수 있습니다 .
I haven't introduced myself yet.
아직 자기 소개를 안 했어요.
My last name is Gu.
내 성은 구(Gu)입니다.
Called Wan 'niang.
Wan'niang이라고 불렀습니다.
I am from the capital city.
저는 수도 출신입니다.
Last month, I came to Bingzhou
지난달에 빙저우에 왔어요
to pay tribute to my ancestors in the name of my father.
내 아버지의 이름으로 내 조상들에게 경의를 표하는 것입니다 .
La familia Gu en Bingzhou.
La familia Gu en Bingzhou.
I remember that Prime Minister Gu
구 총리가 기억나네요
It belongs to the Gu family in Bingzhou as well.
그것도 Bingzhou의 Gu 가족에 속합니다.
I heard that he called Sun Jing out for being a traitor in court.
나는 그가 Sun Jing을 법정에서 배신자라고 불렀다고 들었습니다 .
So, they sent him to jail.
그래서 그들은 그를 감옥에 보냈습니다.
He is my father.
그는 나의 아버지입니다.
In the end, to gain the support of the people,
결국 국민의 지지를 얻으려면
my father was released from prison
우리 아버지는 감옥에서 풀려났어요
and confined at home.
그리고 집에 갇혔어요.
So I traveled to Bingzhou to pay homage to our ancestors
그래서 나는 우리 조상들에게 경의를 표하기 위해 빙저우(Bingzhou)로 여행을 떠났습니다.
and pray for my father.
그리고 아버지를 위해 기도해주세요.
So, you are Prime Minister Gu's daughter.
그럼 당신은 구총리의 딸이군요.
Our country was overthrown
우리나라는 망했다
and my father almost lost his life.
아버지는 거의 목숨을 잃을 뻔했습니다.
Fortunately, I ran into the Zhenxi army today.
다행히 오늘 저는 Zhenxi 군대를 만났습니다 .
And our army is really impressive
그리고 우리 군대는 정말 인상적이에요
y formidable.
와 엄청나다.
I am willing to donate our family's food eaten in Bingzhou to the Zhenxi Army.
나는 Bingzhou에서 우리 가족이 먹은 음식을 Zhenxi 군대에 기부할 의향이 있습니다.
May victory be yours
승리가 당신의 것이 되기를 바랍니다
and claim the capital city soon.
그리고 곧 수도를 차지하세요.
That way, you can not only save people from this danger,
그렇게 하면 이 위험으로부터 사람들을 구할 수 있을 뿐만 아니라,
You can save my father too.
당신도 우리 아버지를 구할 수 있어요.
Prime Minister Gu is loyal
구 총리는 충성스럽다
and now, you are donating the food for our army.
그리고 지금 당신은 우리 군대를 위해 식량을 기부하고 계십니다.
You are indeed the offspring of loyal family.
당신은 참으로 충성스러운 가문의 자손입니다 .
I have a favor to ask.
부탁드릴 게 있어요.
I hope you can give me a hand.
당신이 나에게 도움을 줄 수 있기를 바랍니다.
Forward.
앞으로.
Now the nation is in chaos.
지금 나라는 혼란에 빠졌습니다.
And Bingzhou is far from the capital city.
그리고 Bingzhou는 수도에서 멀리 떨어져 있습니다.
I'm afraid I won't be able to return to the capital city alone.
혼자서는 수도로 돌아갈 수 없을 것 같아 두렵습니다 .
Please agree
동의해주세요
let me travel with the army.
군대와 함께 여행하게 해주세요.
That way, I will be lucky enough to witness
그래야 내가 목격할 수 있는 행운을 얻을 수 있을 거야
the claim of Xichang by the Zhenxi Army.
Zhenxi 군대의 Xichang 주장 .
It is not easy to march with the army.
군대와 함께 행진하는 것은 쉽지 않습니다.
It is not advisable to bring ladies with us.
여성을 데리고 오는 것은 바람직하지 않습니다 .
No matter how difficult it is,
아무리 어려운 일이라도,
I can accept it.
나는 그것을 받아들일 수 있다.
If you are worried about us,
저희가 걱정되신다면,
Qiucui and I can dress like men.
Qiucui와 저는 남자처럼 옷을 입을 수 있어요.
We won't cause you any problems.
우리는 당신에게 어떤 문제도 일으키지 않을 것입니다.
It's better for me to send a team
팀을 보내는 게 나을 것 같아
to accompany you back to the capital city.
당신과 함께 수도로 돌아가려고 합니다.
You are busy with military matters.
당신은 군사 문제로 바쁘다.
I don't want you to lower the size of your army to protect yourself.
나는 당신이 자신을 보호하기 위해 군대의 규모를 줄이는 것을 원하지 않습니다 .
I just need to allow myself
난 그냥 나 자신을 허용하면 돼
follow the army from behind.
군대를 뒤에서 따라오세요.
Okay then.
그럼요.
You can dress like a man
남자처럼 입어도 돼
and join the army.
그리고 군대에 가세요.
Thank you, General.
감사합니다, 장군님.
Stop there.
거기 멈춰라.
Detente.
긴장 완화.
You widow without education.
당신은 교육을 받지 못한 과부입니다.
Mrs. Shen. Teach them about proper etiquette.
쉔 부인. 적절한 에티켓에 대해 가르쳐주세요 .
Yes your Majesty.
예, 폐하.
The crown princess is from the inner court,
왕세녀 는 안뜰 출신이고,
in the front row.
앞줄에.
Lady of the country is from the outer court,
나라의 귀부인은 바깥뜰에서 나오시며
in the first rank.
첫 번째 순위에.
The crown princess has a higher rank.
왕세녀의 지위가 더 높습니다.
The lady of the country should greet the crown princess with a serene.
나라의 여인은 세자빈에게 정중한 인사를 해야 한다.
That?
저것?
Are you saying I should show my respect to her?
내가 그 사람에게 존경심을 표해야 한다는 뜻인가요 ?
Lady of Wei is the wife of the Great Governor.
위씨(魏女)는 대태사(大精主)의 부인이다.
Great governor has achieved great merits.
위대한 통치자는 큰 공덕을 이루었습니다.
So, Your Highness
그럼, 전하
has exempted you from having to greet her with a greeting.
당신이 그녀에게 인사할 필요를 면제해 주었습니다 .
I am the personal lady of His Highness.
저는 전하의 개인 부인입니다.
I am in the sixth rank.
나는 여섯 번째 순위에 있습니다.
You are the servant of the lady of Wei.
당신은 위(魏) 여인의 하인입니다.
You have no ranking.
순위가 없습니다.
Which is it?
무엇 이니?
A maid who has no ranking wants
순위가 없는 메이드가 원하는
to hit a personal lady in the sixth rank?
여섯 번째 순위에 있는 개인 여성을 때리려면 ?
It sounds like you're confused about where you are.
당신 이 어디에 있는지 혼란스러워하는 것 같습니다 .
You have no manners at all.
당신은 전혀 매너가 없습니다.
What a sharp tongue you have.
당신은 정말 날카로운 혀를 가지고 있습니다.
Thank you for the compliment, Madam de Wei.
De Wei 부인님, 칭찬해주셔서 감사합니다.
The Great Governor is humble and courteous.
대지사는 겸손하고 예의가 바르다.
Now that you have entered the palace,
이제 궁궐에 들어왔으니,
you have to follow the rules and proper etiquette too
규칙 과 예절도 지켜야 해요
so that you are not a laughing stock.
그래서 당신은 웃음거리가 되지 않습니다.
A laughable resource.
웃기는 자료입니다.
I want to see
보고 싶어요
who dares to laugh at me now.
지금 감히 나를 비웃는 사람이 누구입니까?
You will be taught a lesson if you have no manners.
매너가 없으면 교훈을 받게 됩니다 .
You...
너...
You're crazy!
넌 미쳤어!
Stop crying.
울음을 멈출.
To be honest,
솔직히 말하자면,
(Duke Zheng) rumors are quite unpleasant.
(정공) 소문이 꽤 불쾌해요.
Sin embargo, Xiao
신 금수조치, 샤오
She is still the princess of the former crown.
그녀는 여전히 이전 왕관의 공주입니다.
Since the former crown prince committed suicide,
전 왕세자가 자살한 이후
I should have followed
내가 따라갔어야 했는데
it made sense.
말이 됐습니다.
Even if he didn't,
그가 그러지 않았더라도,
she should have become a nun to remain loyal to the former crown prince.
그녀는 전 왕세자에게 충성을 유지하기 위해 비구니가 되어야 했습니다 .
great governor
위대한 주지사
He is a wise man.
그는 현명한 사람입니다.
Because
왜냐하면
so he took this woman?
그래서 그 사람이 이 여자를 데려간 거야?
She must have put a spell on him.
그녀는 그에게 주문을 걸었을 것입니다.
Think about it.
생각해 보세요.
With the years,
세월이 흐르면서,
Had married
결혼했다
so many wives and concubines.
아내와 첩이 너무 많아요.
But he had never hated anyone before.
하지만 그는 이전에 누구도 미워한 적이 없었습니다.
I can't allow this to continue.
이런 일이 계속되는 것을 용납할 수 없습니다.
Don't panic.
당황하지 말 것.
There are still countless battles ahead of us.
우리 앞에는 아직도 셀 수 없이 많은 전투가 남아 있습니다 .
The Great Governor still needs the Chenjun Yuan Clan
대지사에게는 여전히 Chenjun Yuan Clan이 필요합니다
fight for him and call him food.
그를 위해 싸우고 그를 음식이라고 부르세요.
He won't treat us badly.
그는 우리를 나쁘게 대하지 않을 것입니다.
But this Xiao
그런데 이 샤오
He is adamant about staying in the palace.
그는 궁전에 머무르는 것에 대해 단호합니다.
Maybe
아마도
He has an ulterior motive.
그에게는 숨은 동기가 있습니다.
We'll find out what it is eventually.
우리는 그것이 무엇인지 결국 알아낼 것입니다.
So,
그래서,
I will discuss this with our relatives
이 문제는 친척들과 논의하겠습니다.
and convince the Great Governor to kill this woman
그리고 대지사에게 이 여자를 죽이라고 설득하세요
for what he did to you.
그 사람이 너한테 한 짓 때문에.
You can go.
당신은 갈 수 있습니다.
The river appears clear and shallow.
강은 맑고 얕아 보입니다.
But how far apart are the river banks?
하지만 강둑은 얼마나 멀리 떨어져 있나요?
The Qixi Festival will be here soon.
Qixi 축제가 곧 다가올 예정입니다.
we saw each other for the first time
우리는 처음으로 만났어요
en la noche de Qixi.
en la noche de Qixi.
If I had known this would happen,
이런 일이 일어날 줄 알았더라면,
We should never have known him.
우리는 그를 결코 알지 말았어야 했습니다.
Why are you saying something so negative again?
왜 또 그렇게 부정적인 말을 하는 거야 ?
Are you crazy yet
아직 미쳤나요?
Still crazy about Lady de Wei?
아직도 Lady de Wei에 열광하시나요?
I have lived in the palace for a long time.
나는 오랫동안 궁전에서 살았습니다.
This kind of thing happens often.
이런 일이 자주 발생합니다.
It's normal for others
남들에겐 당연한 일
favor the one who has power.
권력을 가진 사람을 선호하십시오.
Once you lose power, they will take a step for you.
당신이 권력을 잃으면 그들은 당신을 위해 조치를 취할 것입니다.
Hoy,
외치는 소리,
Madam Wei slapped my personal lady.
웨이 부인이 내 개인 부인을 때렸어요.
If I didn't retaliate,
내가 보복하지 않았다면,
one day,
어느 날,
I would kill myself with poison.
나는 독약으로 자살할 것이다.
Do you think that
당신은 그렇게 생각합니까?
will punish his legal wife
그의 법적 아내를 처벌할 것이다
for me?
나를 위한?
I do not think it does.
나는 그렇게 생각하지 않습니다.
El Clan Yuan de Chenjun
El Clan Yuan de Chenjun
It's your wife's clan.
당신 아내의 일족입니다.
And you have always trusted them.
그리고 당신은 항상 그들을 신뢰해 왔습니다.
I have offended Madam Wei today.
나는 오늘 웨이 부인의 기분을 상하게 했습니다.
She should leave the palace and become a nun.
그녀는 궁을 떠나 비구니가 되어야 한다.
In that way,
그런 식으로,
I won't be a thorn in someone's flesh.
나는 누군가의 육체에 가시가 되지 않을 것입니다.
You're trying to hit me.
당신은 나를 때리려 고합니다.
I would not dare.
나는 감히하지 않을 것입니다.
I'm just afraid that if I stay here,
내가 여기 계속 있으면
I will die one day without knowing what killed me.
나는 언젠가 무엇이 나를 죽였는지 알지 못한 채 죽을 것입니다.
I better become a nun
난 수녀가 되는 게 좋을 것 같아
and stay away from all curses.
모든 저주를 멀리하십시오.
I want to see
보고 싶어요
what monastery
어느 수도원
can handle you.
당신을 처리할 수 있습니다.
You can build a monastery for me.
당신은 나를 위해 수도원을 지을 수 있습니다.
In a quiet and beautiful place.
조용하고 아름다운 곳에서.
I want him to be close to Xichang.
나는 그가 Xichang과 가까워지기를 바랍니다.
That way, it will be easy to visit me.
그러면 나를 방문하는 것이 쉬울 것입니다.
But maybe after leaving the palace,
하지만 아마도 궁전을 떠난 후에는
you will forget everything about me
당신은 나에 대한 모든 것을 잊게 될 것입니다
In a few days.
며칠 안에.
Do you really want to be a nun?
정말로 수녀가 되고 싶나요?
I don't want to stay in the palace anymore.
나는 더 이상 궁전에 머물고 싶지 않습니다.
Lady of Wei
웨이의 여인
He is not a magnanimous person.
그는 관대 한 사람이 아닙니다.
She likes to make things difficult for me.
그녀는 나를 어렵게 만드는 것을 좋아합니다 .
Furthermore, everyone in the palace
게다가 궁궐 안의 모든 사람들이
He has a sharp tongue.
그는 날카로운 혀를 가지고 있습니다.
I don't want to
나는 원하지 않는다
be gossiped about by them already.
이미 그들로부터 험담을 받고 있습니다.
Forget about being nuns.
수녀가 되는 것은 잊어버리세요.
But
하지만
your personal lady, Mrs. Shen,
당신의 개인적인 부인, 쉔 부인,
He seems like someone with a lot of fortune.
그 사람은 재산이 많은 사람인 것 같아요.
Maybe she can become a nun instead of you.
어쩌면 그녀가 당신 대신 수녀가 될 수도 있어요 .
Finally, you have told the truth.
마침내 당신은 진실을 말했습니다.
To preserve the dignity of the Lady of Wei,
위부인의 위엄을 지키기 위해,
do you want to send my maid
내 가정부를 보내시겠어요?
to become a nun.
수녀가 되려고.
Just give me a glass of poisoned liquor.
독주 한 잔만 주세요 .
Mrs. Shen and me
쉔 부인과 나
will drink that poisoned liquor at once.
그 독주를 당장 마시겠습니다.
She is your maid.
그녀는 당신의 하녀입니다.
She offended Madam Wei.
그녀는 웨이 부인을 화나게 했습니다.
I have no choice but to punish her.
나는 그녀를 처벌할 수밖에 없습니다.
And the Lady of Wei's servant?
그리고 위씨의 하인은요?
I offended me.
나는 나를 화나게했다.
You'll
당신은
ask her to become a nun too?
그 사람에게도 수녀가 되어 달라고 부탁해?
Look to you.
너를 봐.
Are
~이다
so eager to win at everything.
모든 일에서 이기기를 너무 열망합니다.
If you act justly and punish that servant too,
주께서 만일 공 의로 행하여 그 종도 벌하시면
I will send Mrs. Shen away to become a nun.
나는 Shen 부인을 비구니가 되도록 보내겠습니다 .
Otherwise, it's not an opportunity.
그렇지 않으면 기회가 아닙니다.
Are you pinching your tunic?
튜닉을 꼬집고 있습니까?
Let me help you.
내가 도와 줄게.
Forget it.
잊어 버려.
I'm better at this than you.
나는 너보다 이 일을 더 잘해.
When you pack up your torn tights last time,
저번에 찢어진 스타킹을 정리할 때
those points were as long as centipedes.
그 점은 지네만큼 길었습니다.
I want to ask you something.
나는 당신에게 뭔가를 물어보고 싶습니다.
Listen
듣다
you're going to let Miss Gu
구 선생님을 놔두실 건가요?
You travel with our army in men's clothing, right?
당신은 남자 옷을 입고 우리 군대와 함께 여행하는 거죠?
Yeah.
응.
She's alone
그녀는 혼자예요
with his maid.
그의 하녀와 함께.
He wants to return to the capital city.
그는 수도로 돌아가고 싶어한다 .
It is a battlefield everywhere.
어디든 전쟁터다.
She can't survive the trip alone.
그녀는 혼자 여행에서 살아남을 수 없습니다.
Instead,
대신에,
can travel together with our army.
우리 군대와 함께 여행할 수 있어요.
This is the first time.
이번이 처음입니다.
This is the first time I see you treating a lady so kindly.
당신 이 여자를 이렇게 친절하게 대하는 모습 은 처음 봤어요 .
Are you going to become
당신은 될 것인가?
a resplendent old woman when there is no war?
전쟁이 없으면 찬란한 노파 ?
No.
아니요.
I really think that
정말 그런 것 같아요
that Miss Gu is a good woman.
구씨는 좋은 여자예요.
It's good enough for you.
그것은 당신에게 충분합니다.
It's good for you.
그것은 당신에게 좋습니다.
It seems that you have fallen in with Miss Gu.
구씨에게 푹 빠진 것 같아요.
¿Yo?
에야디야?
This is easy.
이것은 쉬워요.
I am going to write a letter to Great General Pei
페이 대장군에게 편지를 쓰려고 해요
to propose to you.
당신에게 프로포즈하기 위해.
No.
아니요.
What nonsense are you talking about?
무슨 말도 안되는 소리를하는거야?
You're the one he likes.
그 사람이 좋아하는 사람이 바로 당신이에요.
For the first time,
처음으로,
you allowed a woman
당신은 여자를 허용했다
travel with our army.
우리 군대와 함께 여행하세요.
So stop dragging me into this.
그러니 나를 이것에 끌어들이지 마세요.
What about being a woman?
여자라면 어떨까요?
Look at Lieutenant He of the Cui family.
Cui 가문의 He 중위를 보세요 .
She is smart and cunning.
그녀는 똑똑하고 교활합니다.
And she's good at leading her troops.
그리고 그녀는 군대를 이끄는 데 능숙합니다.
He's so much better than so many men out there.
그는 세상에 있는 많은 남자들 보다 훨씬 낫습니다 .
From what you have said,
당신이 말한 것에서,
It seems that you are in love with the lieutenant
당신은 중위와 사랑에 빠진 것 같습니다
instead of Miss Gu.
미스 구 대신에.
Without sense.
말이 안 돼요.
Has no sense?
말이 없나요?
Lieutenant.
대장 보좌.
The paper mill.
제지 공장.
I recovered the paper mill you left at the inn.
당신이 여관에 두고 온 제지 공장을 되찾았습니다 .
Show me.
보여줘.
But wait.
하지만 기다려.
This is just a paper mill.
이것은 단지 제지 공장입니다.
Why did you leave it on the counter at the inn ?
왜 여관 카운터에 놓아두셨나요 ?
if you were going to send me to look for him?
그를 찾으러 나를 보내실 생각이신가요 ?
Mira.
미라.
This is just a toy
이건 그냥 장난감이에요
that is sold in a market.
시장에서 파는 것입니다.
It is not unique and has no value.
고유하지도 않고 가치도 없습니다.
And it has broken.
그리고 그것은 깨졌습니다.
Why do you keep it?
왜 그것을 유지합니까?
It's broken?
고장 났나요?
Mira.
미라.
It wasn't broken
부서지지 않았어요
when I gave it to the innkeeper.
내가 그것을 여관 주인에게 주었을 때.
It seems that
것 같다
He didn't take good care of him.
그는 그를 잘 돌보지 않았습니다.
It's broken here too.
여기도 깨졌네요.
This is not how you fix it.
이런 식으로 고치는 것이 아닙니다.
You will be cut by the bamboo strip.
당신은 대나무 조각에 의해 잘릴 것입니다.
Let me do it.
내가 해보자.
This type of work is not for you.
이런 종류의 일은 당신에게 적합하지 않습니다.
It's fixed.
고정되었습니다.
Let's attend the Lantern Festival tomorrow night together.
내일 밤 등불 축제에 함께 참석합시다 .
Don't you have to direct the program tomorrow?
내일 프로그램을 직접 지휘해야 하지 않나요 ?
I already named someone else
나는 이미 다른 사람의 이름을 지었습니다.
to do that kind of boring task.
그런 지루한 일을 하려고.
And you?
당신은요?
Do you have to accompany you , Young Master Cui?
꼭 동행해야 합니까 , 최영스승님?
No.
아니요.
It's a deal then.
그렇다면 거래입니다.
See you then.
그때 만나.
Lieutenant.
대장 보좌.
Did you fix the windmill?
풍차는 고쳤나요?
Yeah.
응.
Lieutenant.
대장 보좌.
Let's enjoy the Lantern Festival together at night.
밤에는 등불 축제를 함께 즐기자 .
I have things to do tonight.
오늘 밤에 할 일이 있어요.
I'll pass.
나는 통과 할 것이다.
Are you going to accompany
동행할 것인가
Young Master to the Lantern Festival?
등불 축제에 젊은 스승님?
Sitting under the well-lit shed
조명이 밝은 창고 밑에 앉아
Why do people gossip?
사람들은 왜 험담을 할까요?
I'll pass.
나는 통과 할 것이다.
What do you have to do then?
그러면 무엇을 해야 합니까?
Yo,
에야디야,
I am afraid that the Zhenxi army
Zhenxi 군대가 두렵습니다.
I will do something secretly.
나는 비밀리에 뭔가를 할 것이다.
So I have to keep an eye on them
그래서 나는 그들을 계속 지켜봐야 해요
to find out what your plan is.
당신의 계획이 무엇인지 알아보기 위해.
Alright. I will go with you
괜찮은. 나는 당신과 함께 갈 것이다
to help you.
당신을 돕기 위해.
You do not have to do it.
당신은 그것을 할 필요가 없습니다.
You can keep an eye on Xie Chang'er of the Zhenxi Army for me.
나를 위해 Zhenxi 군대의 Xie Chang'er를 지켜봐 주시면 됩니다 .
It's not just him
그 사람뿐만이 아니야
the man Li Ni trusts,
리니가 신뢰하는 남자,
can gather intelligence from the sound of the wind.
바람 소리로부터 정보를 수집할 수 있습니다 .
You have to watch him closely.
그를 주의 깊게 관찰해야 합니다.
Don't give him any chance to act secretly.
그에게 비밀리에 행동할 기회를 주지 마십시오 .
Ear.
귀.
Why are you pulling such a long face?
왜 그렇게 긴 얼굴을 당기는 걸까요?
Mr. Shiqi has ordered us to behead Han Li in public.
Shiqi 씨는 우리에게 Han Li를 공개적으로 참수하라고 명령했습니다 .
during the Lantern Festival
등불 축제 기간 동안
to make a name for the Zhenxi Army.
Zhenxi 군대의 이름을 만들기 위해.
Yeah.
응.
We have done everything
우리는 모든 것을 다했습니다
according to Mr. Shiqi's order.
Shiqi 씨의 명령에 따라.
but he asked me
그런데 그 사람이 나한테 물었어
to drive away Miss Taozi
미스 타오즈(Taozi)를 쫓아내려고
of the lieutenant.
중위의.
Because?
왜냐하면?
Since someone
누군가부터
Taozi does not want to follow Lieutenant He,
Taozi는 He 중위를 따르고 싶지 않습니다 .
It means that another person in your place wants to follow you.
이는 당신을 대신하는 다른 사람이 당신을 따르고 싶어한다는 것을 의미합니다.
Just do what he said.
그가 말한 대로만 하세요.
But how can I
하지만 어떻게 할 수 있니?
Lure Miss Taozi out?
미스 타오즈(Taozi)를 쫓아내시겠습니까?
Do they knock her out?
그들이 그녀를 기절시키나요?
She uses poison and is cunning.
그녀는 독을 사용하고 교활합니다.
If he had to fight her, he couldn't win.
그녀와 싸워야 한다면 그는 이길 수 없을 것이다.
Your brain
너의 뇌
It is made of wood.
그것은 나무로 만들어졌습니다.
You can just invite her
그녀를 초대하면 됩니다
to enjoy
즐길 수
the Lantern Festival with you.
당신과 함께하는 등불축제.
Here you have.
여기 있습니다.
Think about it.
생각해 보세요.
Miss Taozi.
미스 타오즈.
What if we enjoy
우리가 즐기면 어떨까?
the Lantern Festival together today?
오늘 등불 축제를 같이 할래?
Why do you invite me?
왜 나를 초대합니까?
Because I'm alone today.
오늘은 나 혼자니까.
Others have other things to do.
다른 사람들은 할 일이 있습니다.
And it seems that
그리고 그것은 것 같습니다
you are alone too.
너도 혼자야.
And we
그리고 우리
so you are inviting me
그래서 나를 초대하는 거야
because you are bored.
당신은 지루하기 때문에.
No.
아니요.
No, Miss Taozi.
아니, 미스 타오지.
That's not what I was referring to.
내가 언급한 것은 그게 아니다.
Forget it.
잊어 버려.
Forget what I said.
내가 말한 건 잊어.
Stop there.
거기 멈춰라.
Since you wanted to invite me,
당신이 나를 초대하고 싶어했기 때문에,
then you invite me.
그럼 당신이 나를 초대합니다.
Why are you changing your mind now?
왜 지금 생각을 바꾸시나요?
Who do you think I am?
날 뭘로 봐요?
No. Miss Taozi.
아니요. 미스 타오지.
- Let me explain. - I'm with you.
- 설명하겠습니다. - 난 너랑 같이있어.
Enjoy the Lantern Festival together.
등불축제를 함께 즐겨보세요 .
Thank you, Miss Taozi.
고마워요, 타오즈 선생님.
No need to thank me.
나에게 감사할 필요는 없습니다.
After all, you have saved me from trouble.
결국 당신은 나를 곤경에서 구해주었습니다.
What a problem?
무슨 문제인가요?
Come take a look.
와서 한 번 보세요.
Be careful.
조심하세요.
Why are you dressing like that today?
오늘 왜 그렇게 입어요?
You look beautiful.
당신은 아름다워 보입니다.
Since I'm here to spy on someone,
누군가를 염탐하러 왔기 때문에
Of course I need to change.
물론 나도 변해야 한다.
This is a trick
이건 속임수야
make others let their guard down.
다른 사람들이 경계심을 늦추게 만드세요.
Indeed, you are wise.
참으로 당신은 현명합니다.
Let's get down to business.
사업을 시작합시다.
You are so pretty today.
오늘은 정말 예쁘네요.
I almost couldn't recognize you.
나는 당신을 거의 알아볼 수 없었습니다.
Let's go.
갑시다.
Amazing!
놀라운!
Again!
다시!
Incredible!
믿을 수 없는!
That's great!
훌륭해요!
Windmills,
풍차,
beautiful and fun windmills.
아름답고 재미있는 풍차.
Again!
다시!
Genial.
온화한.
Give me a windmill, please.
풍차 좀 주세요.
Choose one.
하나를 선택하세요.
I take this.
나는 이것을 받아들인다.
Alright.
괜찮은.
Pay for it.
값을 지불하라.
Do you like windmills?
풍차를 좋아하시나요?
Not really.
설마.
But our lieutenant has a windmill
하지만 우리 중위는 풍차를 가지고 있어요
in his notebook.
그의 노트에.
GOOD!
좋은!
And he is always in a good mood
그리고 그 사람은 항상 기분이 좋아요
when you see him every day.
매일 그 사람을 볼 때.
He refused to throw it away.
그는 그것을 버리는 것을 거부했습니다.
when it broke out that day.
그날 터졌을 때.
She even fixed herself.
그녀는 심지어 자신을 고쳤습니다.
But paper mills are not expensive.
그러나 제지 공장은 비싸지 않습니다.
Only two copper coins.
구리 동전은 2개뿐입니다.
It's true.
사실이에요.
I told him the same.
나도 그에게 똑같이 말했다.
I told him we could buy a new one together.
나는 그에게 우리가 함께 새 것을 살 수 있다고 말했습니다.
But she said she wouldn't understand.
그러나 그녀는 이해하지 못할 것이라고 말했습니다.
She said
그녀가 말했다
than to buy a windmill yourself
풍차를 직접 사는 것보다
It wasn't as fun as getting a windmill as a gift.
풍차를 선물로 받는 것만큼 재미는 없었어요 .
So when I just saw that person,
그래서 방금 그 사람을 봤을 때,
I told myself
나는 나 자신에게 말했다
that I wanted someone
내가 누군가를 원했다고
to give me one too.
나한테도 하나 주려고.
I want to see
보고 싶어요
how fun a windmill can be
풍차가 얼마나 재미있을 수 있는지
when it is a gift from someone else.
다른 사람의 선물일 때.
Is that why you asked me to buy it for you?
그래서 나한테 사달라고 한 거야?
I'm sure you feel honored
나는 당신이 영광이라고 확신합니다
to buy something for myself.
나 자신을 위해 뭔가를 사려고.
Yes Yes.
예 예.
But what's so fun
근데 뭐가 그렇게 재밌어?
to get a windmill as a gift?
풍차를 선물로 받으려면?
Why don't I feel the same?
왜 나는 같은 느낌이 들지 않습니까?
Am I dreaming or is the river full of stars?
나는 꿈을 꾸고 있는 걸까 , 아니면 강에 별이 가득한 걸까?
This place is beautiful.
이곳은 아름답습니다.
The stars at Laolan Pass
라오란 고개의 별들
They are much bigger
그들은 훨씬 더 크다
and closer.
그리고 더 가까이.
When you're lying in the desert at midnight,
당신이 한밤중에 사막에 누워 있을 때 ,
The sky is as dark as silk.
하늘은 비단처럼 어둡습니다.
Like you could touch the star
별을 만질 수 있을 것 같은
just extending it.
그냥 연장하면 됩니다.
We have steppe
우리에겐 대초원이 있어요
as far as the eyes can see in Pingliang.
핑량(Pingliang)에서 눈으로 볼 수 있는 한.
When he was young,
그가 어렸을 때,
My father went hunting with me.
아버지는 나와 함께 사냥하러 가셨습니다.
Sometimes, I would fall asleep on the back of the horse.
때로는 말 뒤에서 잠이 들 때도 있었습니다 .
When I woke up and opened my eyes,
잠에서 깨어 눈을 떴을 때,
I could see every star
나는 모든 별을 볼 수 있었다
in the sky.
하늘에.
They looked like sugar crystals that were about to fall.
그들은 곧 떨어질 설탕 결정처럼 보였습니다.
I grew up in the capital.
나는 수도에서 자랐습니다.
After learning to walk,
걷는 법을 배운 후,
always rides alone to go
항상 혼자 타고 가는데
al Wonderland.
알 원더랜드.
The Wonderland is a famous place in the capital city.
이상한 나라는 수도의 유명한 곳입니다 .
It is located on high ground.
고지대에 위치하고 있습니다.
On,
에,
you can overlook the entire capital city.
수도 전체를 내려다볼 수 있습니다.
Hear the fox and the chirp in the forest, see the rainbow on the other side.
숲속의 여우와 지저귀는 소리를 듣고 반대편에는 무지개를 보세요.
Feel the west breeze in the wonders.
경이로움 속에서 서풍을 느껴보세요 .
Keep riding deep into the sunset.
계속해서 일몰 속으로 깊숙이 들어가세요.
May the sun never set.
해가 지지 않기를 바랍니다.
So, you like this poem.
그래서 당신은 이 시를 좋아합니다.
But I like the other one.
하지만 나는 다른 하나를 좋아해요.
Wait.
기다리다.
I know which one you like.
나는 당신이 어느 것을 좋아하는지 압니다.
That?
저것?
There is grass everywhere on the prairie.
초원 곳곳에 풀이 있다 .
Each year, it will wither during the fall.
매년 가을이 되면 시들게 됩니다.
But you can never burn it.
하지만 절대 태울 수는 없습니다.
Will be back again when spring is here.
봄이 오면 다시 돌아올게요 .
Is that the only one?
그게 유일한가요?
How do you know I like that poem?
내가 그 시를 좋아한다는 걸 어떻게 알죠 ?
Know your enemies well so you can defeat them.
적을 잘 알아야 그들을 물리칠 수 있습니다.
See
보다
that Li Ni is someone like that.
리니가 그런 사람이라고요.
That's why I know
그래서 난 알아요
that you like this poem.
당신이 이 시를 좋아한다고요.
You're amazing, Lieutenant.
정말 대단해요, 중위님.
You are my close friend.
당신은 나의 친한 친구입니다.
I like that.
나는 그것을 좋아한다.
Without sense.
말이 안 돼요.
I did not say
나는 말하지 않았다
I am your bosom friend.
나는 당신의 가슴 친구입니다.
that you said that
네가 그렇게 말했잖아
Why is my dress wet?
내 드레스는 왜 젖어 있나요?
This is bad. The boat is leaking.
이것은 나쁘다. 보트가 새고 있습니다.
♪ If I forget the waste of time ♪
♪시간낭비를 잊어버리면 ♪
♪ Wait for the memories ♪
♪ 추억을 기다려요 ♪
♪ smash and sink ♪
♪ 부수고 가라앉는다 ♪
♪ The emotional scars on your heart ♪
♪ 마음속의 감정적 상처 ♪
♪ They are the mess ♪
♪ 엉망이야 ♪
♪ I find it difficult to let go ♪
♪놓기가 힘들어요 ♪
♪ If the longing is not forgotten ♪
♪그리움이 잊혀지지 않는다면 ♪
♪ I long to return to the first moment ♪
♪나는 처음의 순간으로 돌아가고 싶다 ♪
♪ The affection we had in our fateful situation ♪
♪ 운명적인 상황 속에서도 우리가 가졌던 애정 ♪
♪ How I wish to keep it for you ♪
♪당신을 위해 그것을 간직하고 싶습니다 ♪
♪ If you still remember love ♪
♪아직 사랑을 기억하고 있다면 ♪
♪ The promises we made ♪
♪우리가 한 약속들♪
♪ Even if this love hurts me ♪
♪ 이 사랑이 나를 아프게 해도 ♪
♪ I will continue living for you ♪
♪나는 계속 당신을 위해 살아갈 거예요 ♪
♪ holding on to memories ♪
♪추억을 붙잡고 ♪
♪ Wait it's my persistence ♪
♪ 잠깐만요 이건 내 고집이에요 ♪
♪ If love remembers ♪
♪사랑이 기억한다면 ♪
♪ The promise I made to you ♪
♪너와 한 약속♪
♪ Despite going against destiny ♪
♪운명을 거스르면서도 ♪
♪ I don't regret loving you ♪
♪당신을 사랑한 걸 후회하지 않아요 ♪
♪ I am willing to sacrifice you ♪
♪나는 기꺼이 당신을 희생하겠습니다 ♪
♪ While waiting for your response ♪
♪당신의 응답을 기다리는 동안 ♪
♪ If love is remembered ♪
♪사랑이 기억된다면 ♪
♪ The promise I made to you ♪
♪너와 한 약속♪
♪ Despite going against destiny ♪
♪운명을 거스르면서도 ♪
♪ I don't regret loving you ♪
♪당신을 사랑한 걸 후회하지 않아요 ♪
♪ I am willing to sacrifice you ♪
♪나는 기꺼이 당신을 희생하겠습니다 ♪
♪ While I wait for your response ♪
♪당신의 응답을 기다리는 동안 ♪